[MYCROFT]
Regarding the Jack the Ripper
incident from the other day.
[MYCROFT]
A common enemy appeared before
the Yard and the public
moments before chaos ensued.
Within the blink of an eye,
hostility turned to solidarity.
One might say it
offered a brief glimpse
into the Moriarty Plan,
frankly speaking.
[ALBERT grunts]
Nonetheless, this incident...
[MYCROFT]
Indeed, it is not over yet.
Despite the fact "Jack the
Ripper" is no longer among us,
the Yard has still
arrested a suspect.
[LOUIS] Obviously,
they've falsely accused
this man based on
fabricated evidence.
[WILLIAM] Yes, after
allowing Jack to escape,
the Yard is disgraced.
Of course, they would resort
to such extreme measures.
No surprise.
So, what's the plan?
First, we set this
innocent man free.
Then find the person
that accused him
and see that they
receive their just rewards.
[ALBERT] In short, following
your brother's decision,
we will allow the
case to go unsolved and
remain just that--a mystery.
[MYCROFT]
I wish for your success, Albert.
Best of luck.
You're doing rather fine work,
you and your two brothers.
How kind, I hope the
same for you and yours.
Yes, that depends
entirely on him.
[HOLMES grunts]
[CITIZEN 17A]
Send out Jack!
[CITIZEN 17B]
Hang the scoundrel by the neck!
[CITIZEN 17C] What's the wait?
Bring him to justice!
[PATERSON]
Hell of a commotion out there.
[gasps] Paterson.
It's looking an awful lot like
Bloody Sunday, don't you think?
That town doctor we arrested,
the man has a clean record.
The officers were
following direct orders
from Chief Inspector Arterton.
Apparently, they found evidence
he was involved in the murders.
What do you think?
[PATERSON] Hm. The fact that
you're asking me that question
means you have
doubts about the arrest;
that we've the wrong man.
[LESTRADE grunts]
[AMES] Oh! Good day,
Chief Inspector Arterton.
[ARTERTON] Not until you
silence the rabble outside!
All of them, sir?
Just drag two or three of
their leaders out of the crowd!
Duff 'em up proper,
and toss 'em back out
as an example!
[AMES]
We can't do that, sir.
[LESTRADE] Our Jack the Ripper
is likely falsely accused.
And if I had to guess,
Arterton's behind it.
And do you have any proof?
I mean, let's be frank.
We are talking
about our boss here.
The CID's top man.
[LESTRADE grunts]
Arterton has a history
of using what some
might call heavy-handed tactics
in order to produce results.
There's a reason he got
promoted to where he is today.
And considering
how Jack the Ripper
escaped right from
under his nose,
it was only a matter of time
before heads began to roll.
Ample motivation to falsify
evidence if you were he.
[gasps] And we're going
to let him go unchallenged
while he convicts
an innocent man?
Scotland Yard is supposed
to uphold the law!
Kindly lower your voice.
[LESTRADE]
You're-- You're right.
So, how are you going to
prove the charges are false?
Working on it.
Well, you had
better hurry yourself,
because he will
likely confess to the crimes
following Arterton's
script to the letter.
[LESTRADE grunts]
[PATERSON] I don't know
if you're aware of this,
but Arterton keeps
a secret ledger.
[LESTRADE]
A ledger?
Of course! For a lie this size,
there has to be a lot of
off-the-books money at play.
If we could track down any money
diverted from the investigation,
that'd be all the
evidence we need.
Truly, the definitive
proof required.
The only question is where
does Arterton keep the ledger?
[PATERSON]
I'd wager the classified
materials room on
the fifth floor.
[PATERSON] The chief
inspector is in charge of it.
No one enters
without his permission.
Come on, side-stepping
Arterton? It's impossible!
[PATERSON]
Hmph. And at times like this,
I believe you call on him.
Your friend, the great
consulting detective.
You're referring to Holmes?
[LESTRADE clears throat]
[LESTRADE]
I highly doubt he'll show any
interest in a treasure hunt.
[HERDER] Welcome. I've been
expecting your arrival,
Mister Bonde.
[HERDER]
I took the liberty of having
everything necessary
prepared in this case.
As you know, this will
be an infiltration mission.
Thus, silence is key.
That's why instead
of relying on powder,
this gun fires
using air pressure.
The bullets you see there
have been loaded
with a sleeping agent.
So, if you shoot into a wall,
the gas will be released,
rendering anybody unlucky
enough to be nearby unconscious.
[BONDE]
Very nice, you've come through.
Tell me, Herder.
What might that be over there?
Hah! Caught your
attention, I see.
You have a keen eye,
Mister Bonde.
Presenting my
latest engineering feat.
[grunts]
A specially engineered autocar!
[CITIZENS shout]
[ARTERTON grunts, growls]
[knocking]
[AMES]
Excuse me, sir.
- -[door opens]
- -[ARTERTON] Hm?
[ARTERTON]
Yes, Ames, what do you want?
The suspect's lawyer is here
and is demanding to
speak with his client.
We can't have him
getting any ridiculous ideas
before we obtain a confession.
Tell the lawyer that there's
an emergency or something.
That'll send him away.
I'll have this whole
matter sewn up by morning!
[AMES]
Yes, sir.
[PATERSON]
He's on edge.
It's that late?
Just about time for
my meeting with him.
[PATERSON] Appears this man
is not the punctual type.
[car rumbles]
[PATERSON]
Hm?
[CITIZENS gasp, murmur]
[BONDE]
Sorry for running late.
[BARTENDER 17A]
Evening, sir.
What can I get for you?
Five parts brandy to
one-part maraschino, stirred.
With Angostura bitters,
three dashes, if you would.
Three? Very good.
I'll have that ready
in just a moment.
You're drawing an awful
lot of attention.
[BONDE] It took some
time for its creator
to explain the gears and get
his permission to borrow it.
But not as long as it would
have taken me to arrive here
if I had ridden by
carriage instead.
[PATERSON]
Hm. Point taken.
Headquarters is on
high alert at the moment
thanks to Arterton's orders.
Just to get in it'll
require a double check.
Meaning I can't sneak
you inside on my own.
[MAN 17A]
Oh, come on now, luv.
Yeah, you.
That local doctor
the Yard arrested.
He's already endured hours
of harsh interrogation.
We need to resolve
this affair soon,
before they elicit
a false confession from him.
[BONDE] The secret ledger--
where is it hidden?
We know it's located in the
classified materials room,
but the only way in
is with Arterton's permission.
He has his own hand-picked
officers guarding it.
Your as-yet-unnamed
cocktail, sir. Enjoy.
Many thanks.
That's no obstacle; there isn't
anything I'm not able to steal.
You're very confident.
Would you care for one?
It takes an already
acerbic beverage
and makes it harsher so
you savour the bitters.
Thank you, but no.
[BONDE grunts]
It's quite good.
Think I'll call
this a "Paterson."
Returning to the topic at hand,
you have to find some way
to infiltrate headquarters.
Say, what about disguising
yourself as Lestrade?
- -[glass clatters]
- -Better yet...
I don't want to
have a drink with you!
[BARTENDER 17A]
Sir, please stop this at once.
[MAN 17A] What's the harm?
Just one little drink.
I prefer a more direct approach.
[WOMAN 17A]
Keep your hands off me!
[MAN 17A groans]
You're clearly bothering
the lady, drunken buffoon.
[MAN 17A]
Hey! What'd you call me?
[WOMAN 17A]
Thank you!
Not at all; it's my pleasure.
- -[glass shatters]
- -[WOMAN 17A gasps]
You tryin' to steal
my date? I'll kill you!
[BONDE chuckles]
[clang]
[PATERSON] Because of
the heightened security,
they can't waste much time
dealing with drunkards.
Consider yourself lucky
the officers didn't bother
to frisk you thoroughly.
[BONDE] I got inside
the building, didn't I?
[sighs] I brought
some good news.
Lestrade just returned
from his errand.
He's asking for me.
He has a guest with him--
someone whom he couldn't
get admitted
thanks to the double checks
we've implemented.
I think I know
where this is going.
[PATERSON]
Yes, just as you hoped.
The great consulting
detective has arrived.
Meaning all of
the players are here.
Time to begin the operation.
[ARTERTON panting]
Doesn't seem to be protesting
his innocence anymore.
Take over from here.
[AMES]
Very well, sir.
[CITIZENS]
Send out the Ripper!
[PATERSON]
I'm impressed you managed
to convince Holmes to show up.
Truth is, it should've
been harder,
but before I could even explain
the situation to him, he said:
I guarantee the man
in custody was framed.
I'll assist you.
His words.
You're quite the
negotiator, Lestrade.
Sherlock, I know you
want to exonerate this man,
but an expedition
through Scotland Yard?
For a ledger that
may not even exist?
Look, John,
I told you the true story about
Jack the Ripper, didn't I?
I still need to
verify something.
Understood.
[HOLMES]
I know it was the Lord of Crime
who solved the Ripper slayings,
and if he really does
fancy himself Robin Hood,
he'll most likely step in
concerning this
unjustified arrest.
Problem is,
if I'm not careful
how I go about this,
I'll upset the chain
of events he had planned.
Worst case scenario,
that means being unable
to rescue an innocent man.
- -[HOLMES groans]
- -[WATSON gasps]
[HOLMES]
That miserable sod!
He infuriates me every time!
Of course, he accounted
for me being here tonight.
At no point have I had
the freedom to make
a single decision.
The way things are going,
I'll be trapped in the
palm of his hand forever!
[WATSON]
Sherlock.
Sherlock!
[HOLMES gasps]
The inspector was about
to lead us upstairs.
Oh, right-o.
[HOLMES]
Fine then, I'll go along
and make the choices
I believe are right.
It's up to me whether
I play his game or not.
[LESTRADE grunts]
[BOTH groan]
We weren't sleeping
on the job, I swear!
Access to this wing's
restricted, sir.
I have business in the
classified materials room.
And as you can see,
Chief Inspector Arterton
supplied me with
the key to get inside.
[LESTRADE]
Which of course is a blatant lie
only Holmes could
convince me would work.
After you.
[HOLMES]
Right.
Beg your pardon, Inspector,
but no one informed us you
would be demanding access.
[LESTRADE]
It concerns something that
came up rather suddenly.
[GUARD 17A]
So, these two are--?
Let's go.
Inspector!
These two are helping
with the investigation.
They also have Chief Inspector
Arterton's authorization.
The chief inspector
gave his key to Lestrade?
Does that sound right?
No.
[LESTRADE]
There's the room!
The rest is up to you, Holmes.
[HOLMES]
Sure. Leave it to me.
[lock clinks]
[BONDE gasps]
[BONDE]
Sherlock!
[BONDE chuckles]
[BONDE blows]
[ARTERTON]
Hold it!
That was fast.
I can't wait to hear
your explanation, Lestrade.
During a crisis
while we're in lockdown,
not only do you
enter a restricted area
without my permission, but you
bring civilians with you!
Answer me! Just what
are you plotting?
[gasps] And we're going
to let him go unchallenged
while he convicts
an innocent man?
Scotland Yard is
supposed to uphold the law!
The case against the doctor
needs to be re-examined.
Wh-What was that?
[LESTRADE]
You heard me.
I believe the man in our custody
has been wrongly accused!
[ARTERTON grunts] Lestrade,
you would dare to defy me?
[LESTRADE]
On the other side of that door,
there's proof that'll
back up my claim.
A ledger that shows you
falsified evidence!
[gasps, grunts]
You're the one peddling lies!
- -[ARTERTON grunts]
- -[LESTRADE groans]
If I say a man's guilty,
then he is guilty!
And I will never give you
my permission to go in there!
If you try breaking into this
room just one more time,
I'll have you
immediately arrested!
[LESTRADE]
Based on his reaction,
no question remains--
the ledger's behind that door.
[grunts]
- -[thudding]
- -[ARTERTON, LESTRADE grunting]
- -[WATSON gasps]
- -[OFFICERS shouting]
[OFFICER 17A]
Inspector, please!
Enough!
I won't let you convict an
innocent man, you hear me?
[LESTRADE grunts]
Lestrade's got
some fight in him.
Right.
[LESTRADE]
I said let me go!
[ARTERTON groans]
Someone, go and get help!
Toss Lestrade into
a cell, you hear me?!
Yes, sir.
[ARTERTON, OFFICERS,
LESTRADE yelling]
Well, John, c'mon.
What? But Inspector Lestrade...
[HOLMES]
Never mind.
My word,
how many more friends will
I have to visit down here?
[LESTRADE]
Paterson?
That was far too rash,
even for you.
I feel so ashamed.
[PATERSON chuckles]
Rash, but not surprising.
Brought you something.
[gasps] You mean-- That isn't...
It can't be!
Arterton's secret ledger.
Whilst you were having
your donnybrook in
the classified materials room.
I dipped into his
office and lifted it.
Despite saying it wasn't
there to begin with.
[laughing]
Yes, well, in retrospect,
I ended up treating you
and the others as decoys.
I apologize.
Happy to oblige.
As long as it helps
save an innocent man,
you'll get no
complaints from me.
[PATERSON] All that
remains is for you to hand
the ledger over to Holmes.
Seems Arterton's time
as head of the CID
is rapidly drawing to a close.
And I for one can't wait!
Leave it to me, Paterson!
[PATERSON] It appears
everything is going to work,
but I have to say...
[PATERSON]
Hell's bells.
That chap is bloody mad.
[PATERSON]
Still, though,
our mutual friend admitted
him into the organization.
So, he must be good.
[PATERSON chuckles]
Is that the article
about the Ripper case?
It is. Looks like the disgraced
chief inspector's out of a job.
As for the rest of his cronies,
seems they got the axe, as well.
[WATSON grunts]
Perhaps most importantly,
a citizen having
nothing to do with the case
is no longer behind bars.
And Lestrade's show of courage
was a surprise, as well.
[HOLMES]
I suppose.
[HOLMES] This whole
"Jack the Ripper "incident
and the false accusation--
he secretly insinuated
himself into both cases,
and solved them more
favourably than I would have.
Only one truth can
be derived from this.
He is a Robin Hood--
there's no mistaking that.
But at the same time,
he's also a criminal.
Makes me wonder.
True, he rescued
an innocent man,
but was setting him free
his only objective?
[BARTENDER 17A]
Evening, sir.
What can I get for you?
[PATERSON]
Well, let's see.
How about a brandy
and maraschino?
With Angostura bitters,
three dashes, please.
Excellent choice of drink, sir.
Sounds like one unusual
cocktail you've ordered there.
[PATERSON chuckles]
A friend of mine's rather
partial to drinking them.
And they've gotten me curious
as to how they taste now.
I see.
You know, I'm sorry things
turned out the way they did.
[PATERSON] Everyone wanted
you to throw that punch.
"The hero who managed to lance
that collective boil of ours."
When you put it that way, sounds
like you're the real hero.
If it hadn't been
for you taking action,
things would have ended up
a lot differently.
[PATERSON]
Hm.
Everything worked out fine.
Besides I've been
wanting to get out
and pursue cases in
the field a little more.
[PATERSON chuckles]
Knowing you, that doesn't
surprise me in the least.
Thank you both for waiting;
here's two Patersons.
Huh?
[PATERSON chuckles]
[LESTRADE] My apologies for
leaving you all the hassle
and paperwork that comes
with the chief inspector's post.
[PATERSON]
Don't mention it.
We're chums, aren't we?
[LESTRADE] Cheers,
Paterson, to your promotion.
[glass clinks]
[LESTRADE]
Ugh, too bitter!
[WILLIAM] The corruption
within the Yard has been purged,
and the top CID post
has been reassigned.
Coincidentally, our inside
man has moved up in rank.
Thanks to his new title,
he'll be of great use to us.
Another step closer
to the Moriarty Plan.
We're almost there.
[BONDE] Next time
on Moriarty the Patriot  :
"The Merchant of London."